Guide to the Fred W. Voget Papers 1935-1996
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Fred W. Voget Papers
1935-1996
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 318
Voget, Fred W., 1913-1997
13.0 linear feet
This collection represents a large portion of the academic research and writing career of cultural anthropologist and American Indian ethnologist Fred W. Voget. Voget focused his research for many years on the Crow tribe, also called Apsaalooké, of Montana.
Biographical Note
Frederick William Voget, cultural anthropologist and American Indian ethnologist, was born in Salem, Oregon, on February 12, 1913. He was one of six children of Friedrich A. Voget, who emigrated from Germany to Oregon when he was 19, and Fay Isham, whose grandparents were Oregon pioneers. Voget was educated in Portland public schools, attended Reed College, and graduated from the University of Oregon. He attended graduate school at Yale University and received a Ph.D. in Anthropology in 1947. Fred served in the 71st Division of the U.S. Infantry from 1942 to 1947 and was honorably discharged as a Master Sergeant. He married Mary Kay Mee in 1942 and they had three daughters, Antoinette, Colleen, and Jane. Mrs. Voget worked as Dr. Voget's research assistant throughout their many years together.
Dr. Voget's fieldwork and doctoral dissertation subjects were the Crow Indians of Montana. His dissertation, The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance, was published in 1984 in the Civilization of the American Indians Series, University of Oklahoma Press, and is the first full-length authoritative treatment of the Crow Sun Dance. Holt Rinehart published A History of Ethnology, an earlier book, in 1975. Recent contributions to new books include the introduction to Old Man Coyote and the foreword to Yellowtail, Crow Indian Medicine Man. His most recent book, They Call Me Agnes, was a finalist for the Western Writers of America Spur Award for the best non-fiction book of 1995. They Call Me Agnes, the life story of Agnes Yellowtail Deernose, a Crow Indian woman, was written with the assistance of his wife, Mary Kay Mee.
Dr. Voget was the author of many articles, notable among them "The Osage Indians, Osage Research Report" (New York, London, 1974) and "Crow Sacred Numerology" published in the Plains Anthropologist in 1996. His articles are also published in the 1996 Encyclopedia of Cultural Anthropology sponsored by Yale University.
Fred Voget taught at McGill University in Montreal, the University of Arkansas, the University of Toronto, and Southern Illinois University. He was a visiting professor at Northwestern University and Portland State University. In 1966 he won a Canada Council Research Grant to work with the Six Nations tribes of Eastern Canada. He was a Fulbright Scholar to Germany in 1972 and returned there in 1979 as a visiting professor at the University of Munich. After his retirement as Professor Emeritus from Southern Illinois University, Fred returned to Portland where he continued to write and lecture. He was an adjunct professor at Portland State University and was a guest lecturer at the University of Oregon and Linfield College.
Since 1939 Dr. Voget devoted his life and his research to recording and preserving the culture and way of life of the Crow as it was and is. His contribution to the study of ethnology was intended to improve the lives of American Indians and to promote understanding and respect for the diversity of cultures in the world. He was an adopted member of the Crow Tribe and spent part of every summer with them in Montana. Fred W. Voget died on 8, 1997
This collection represents a large portion of the academic research and writing career of Fred W. Voget from his undergraduate years in the 1930s to a few years before his death in 1997. While the bulk of his research was focused on the Crow Tribe, the collection also includes secondary source research on numerous other North American tribes and primary source research on the Iroquois, Shoshoni, and Blackfeet Indians. Research specific to the Crow Tribe includes bibliographies, annotated photocopies of papers, book chapters, and articles, interviews spanning half of century from 1939 to 1993, and photographs from 1939 to 1987
The collection is divided into six series:
Series I: General Anthropology and Native American research, undated, 0.7 linear feet
Series II: Crow Indian research, 5.0 linear feet, 1936-1995
Series III: Field research notebooks, 1.0 linear feet, 1949-1993
Series IV: Crow language research, 1.0 linear feet, undated
Series V: Writings, 2.3 linear feet, 1935-1996
Series VI: Photographs, 2.5 linear feet, 1939-1989
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
The materials in this collection were retained by the Voget Family until donation to the K. Ross Toole Archives.
Gift of Mary Kay Voget, 2001. Dissertation purchased in 2004.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Anthropologists--United States; Ethnologists--United States
Blackfeet Indians; Crow Indians; Crow Indians--Photographs; Crow Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Crow language; Indians of North America; Iroquois Indians; Shoshoni Indians; Siksika Indians
Photographs
Montana; Photographs; Native Americans
- General Anthropology and Native American research, undated; Series I; 0.7 linear feet
  This series includes notes and readings on anthropology theory and practice, bibliographies of anthropology readings, and a small amount of anthropology research notes. Additionally, the series has reading notes and bibliographies on a number of Native American tribes. The arbitrary arrangement begins with general anthropology and moves into broad Native American topics.
  - Anthropology theory notes, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Anthropology and ethnology theory notes, undated (Box-folder 1/2)
  - General bibliography of anthropology and archeology readings, undated (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Bibliography regarding culture, history, and evolution, undated (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Card file of book release notices, various authors, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
  - General anthropology notes regarding "constancy of problems", undated (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Anthropology graduate class planning notes, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Research notes, culture typology, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Shorthand practice notes, undated (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Pamphlet, "A Preliminary Consideration of Areas of Africa", 1924 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Notes on Central Mexico cultures, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Notes and bibliography, South America, undated (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Miscellaneous notes taken in Southwest Museum, December 1937 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Report and discussion on Dobu Islanders, Apache Kinship, Australian Tribes, Primitive Behavior, and Iroquois Women, undated (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Excerpt regarding Shawnee and Delaware Indians from unnamed report, undated (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Pawnee, mimeographed information, undated (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Arapahoe reading notes, undated (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Kiowa reading notes, undated (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Algonquin reading notes, undated (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Native Americans, reading notes, undated (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Brief news article on origin of corn, undated (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Native American population according to 1910 census, undated (Box-folder 2/2)
  - General Native American bibliography, undated (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Bibliography, general Plains tribes, undated (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Bibliography, brief, U.S. Government, undated (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Bibliography, fur trade, undated (Box-folder 2/6)
- Crow Indian research, 1936-1995; Series II; 5.0 linear feet
  This series includes bibliographies, research notes on readings, annotated and clean copies of materials, newspaper articles, contact information, and interview notes. The bulk of the series is Crow Indian research, but material such as interviews with Shoshoni tribe members have been included to duplicate Voget's synthesis of this research in his book The Shoshoni-Crow Sun Dance. While the broad order of this series is arbitrary, Voget's original card file order has been maintained. Cards in "to be filed" groups were filed according to established categories and notes not on cards have been inserted into separate folders according to those same categories or topics. Groupings of interviews have been maintained as much as possible.
  - Notes on Frank Bird Linderman's Red Mother, undated (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Notes on 30, 1920 Report Commissioner of Indian Affairs, undated (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Notes on Crow Indian Shelters and information on Fort Belnap Indian Arts and Crafts and the Blackfeet Indian Reservation, undated (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Miscellaneous Crow research notes and memorabilia, undated (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Crow names with abbreviations (informants), undated (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Indian education specialist address & agency location note, undated (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Crow Agency news articles, 1973, 1993 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Crow news articles including reburial of Chief Black Foot, Donald Deernose obituary, and a Henrietta Whiteman profile, 1978, 1979 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Miscelleaneous news articles, undated (Box-folder 2/15)
  - References on Crow art, undated (Box-folder 2/16)
  - List of museums, undated (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Bibliography notes, undated (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Early research bibliography on Crow, undated (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Crow bibliography, alphabetized, undated (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Crow bibliographical sources, no order, undated (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Bibliography, Crow and other North American tribes, undated (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Bibliography, Crow and other North American tribes, undated (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Notes on "Phonetic Transcription of Indian Language," Report of Committee of AAA, original 1916, notes, undated (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Pre-history notes and bibliography, Crow, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Notes from Blankets and Moccasins: Plenty Coups and his People, the Crows, author Gwendolin Damon Wagner, published 1936, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Notes from The Oregon Trail, author Francis Parkman, published 1931, undated (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Notes from Meldrum's account in The Indian Journals, undated (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Notes from Peter Nabakov's Two Leggings: The Making of a Crow Warrier, undated (Box-folder 3/7)
  - List of some Crow clans, undated (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Typed copies of various reservation agency reports, 1885-1894 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Notes on Crow history, undated (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Miscellaneous short notes, Crow, undated (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Analysis of dating Crow-Hidatsa separation, 1991 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Copy of article, "Notes on Crow-Hidatsa Schism", 1977 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Copy of chapters from The Crow Tribe of Indians by Norman Plummer, 1974 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Copy of sections from Early Western Travels, Reuben Gold Thwaites, ed. 1904, 1966 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Copies of articles on Plains Indians by J.D. Keyser, 1979, 1993 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Annotated copy of "The Crow Migration Story," Archeology in Montana, 1979 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Copy of "Ethnohistoric Problems in the Crow-Hidatsa Separation," Archaeology in Montana, 1979 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Copy of "The North American Berdarche," from Current Anthropology, 1983 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Copy of pages from The Missouri Indians, 1960 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Annotated copy of portions of The Indian Journal by Lewis Henry Morgan, 1959 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Copy of "Journal of Laroque" from Canadian Archives, 1911 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Copy of chapters from Narratives of the Adventures of Zenas Leonard, 1934 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Abstracts of papers from Montana Archeological Society Annual Meeting, 1978 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - Copy of "Plains Indian Sun/Dance," by Spier, 1921 (Box-folder 3/25)
  - B.I.A. "programming for Indian Social and Economic Improvement", 1956-04-12 (Box-folder 3/26)
  - Copy of M.A. Thesis "Abaatassheek: The Oilers, Pentecostalism Among the Crow Indians", 1993 (Box-folder 3/27)
  - Annotated copy of "Apsaakisshe: A Description of the Crow Indian Sun Dance,", undated; John A. Grim (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Annotated copies of portions of Indians in the Fur Trade, 1974; Arthur J. Ray (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Annotated copy of pages from The Fur Trade in the Upper Missouri, 1840, 1865, 1965; John E. Sunder (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Annotated copies of portions of The Missouri Fur Trade, 1840, 1865, undated (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Annotated copies of chapters from Curtis's The North American Indian, undated (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Annotated copy of "The Sundance" from Curtis's The North American Indian, undated (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Annotated copy of "War and Chase" from Curtis's The North American Indians, undated (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Annotated copy of "Myth & Legend" from Curtis's The North American Indian, undated (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Annotated copy of partial chapter "The Apsaroke," from Curtis's The North American Indian, undated (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Annotated copy of "Religion and Ceremonies" from Curtis's The North American Indian, 1920 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Copy of chapter on Crow peyotism, author unknown, undated (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Copy of The Stars We Know: Crow Indian Ethnoastronomy, 1994; Timothy McCleary (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Annotated copy of "The Sun Dance of the Wind River Shoshoni and Ute", 1919; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Annotated copy of Social Life of the Crow Indians, 1912; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Annotated copy of Myths and Traditions of the Crow Indians, 1918; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Copy of Societies of the Crow, Hidatsa, and Mandan Indians, 1913; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Annotated copy of "Crow Sun Dance", 1915; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Annotated copy of "Tobacco Society of the Crow Indians", 1919 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Annotated copy of "The Material Culture of the Crow Indians", 1922; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Annotated copy of "Crow Indian Art", 1922; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Annotated copy of "Minor Ceremonies of the Crow Indians", 1924; Robert Lowie (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Annotated copy of "Towards a "New" North American Legal History", 1986; Frederick Hoxie (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Annotated copy of "A Culture Which Has Been Inevitably Disintegrated", 1987; Frederick Hoxie (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Annotated copy of "Building a Future on the Past: Crow Indian Leadership in an Era of Division and Reunion", 1984; Frederick Hoxie (Box-folder 5/5)
  - New book information sheet on Frederick Hoxie book release, 1988 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Annotated book draft entitled "From Individualism to Bureaucracy: Documents on the Crow Indians, Part 1, Chapter I/IV, 1920, 1945-1974; Charles and Susanna Bradley (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Annotated book draft entitled "From Individualism to Bureaucracy: Documents on the Crow Indians, Part 1, Chap. V/conclusion, 1920-1945, 1974; Charles and Susanna Bradley (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Annotated book draft entitled "From Individualism to Bureaucracy: Documents on the Crow Indians, Part 2, 1920-1945, 1974; Charles and Susanna Bradley (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Annotated book draft entitled "From Individualism to Bureaucracy: Documents on the Crow Indians, Part 3, 1920-1945, 1974; Charles and Susanna Bradley (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Annotated book draft entitled "From Individualism to Bureaucracy: Documents on the Crow Indians, Part 4, 1920-1945, 1974; Charles and Susanna Bradley (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Annotated copy of "An Ethnohistorical Analysis of Crow Political Alliances", 1977; Katherine M. Weist (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Copy of paper entitled "Crow Peyotism", 1963; Robert C. Kiste (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Copy of "The History of Peyotism in Nevada", 1982; Omer C. Stewart (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Copy of "Friend to the Ute", 1982; Omer C. Stewart (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Annotated copy of "An Archeological Demonstration of Migration on the Northern Plains", 1978; William J. Byrne (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Copy of "Crow Rendezvous", 1981; Colin Taylor (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Copy of "Early Nineteenth Century Crow Warrior Costume", 1984; Colin Taylor (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Copy of University of Montana Vision magazine with "Indian Law Clinic" article, 1990 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Review of Soldiers Falling into Camp, 1992; William W. Savage, Jr. (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Paper entitled "An Early Basket and Plum-Stone Game of Chance Played by Cheyenne Women", 1990; Reno Charlette (Box-folder 6/6)
  - J. E. Ransom's correspondence regarding the Medicine Wheel, 1994 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Small copy of 1855 map of Crow Country from unnamed source, undated (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Misc. research on Crow land use and labor statistics, 1949, 1975, 1976 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Copy of U.S. Dept. of Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs Land Use and Production Records, 1974 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs statistics on Crow, 1983, 1987, undated (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Copy of Koittai Hilik, Crow newspaper, 1977 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Copy of "Second Battle of the Big Horn: Indian Voting Rights Suit," in The Nation news magazine, 1986-10-25; Wilbur Wood (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Copy of Supreme Court Case, Montana et. al. v. United States et. al. regarding hunting and fishing rights, 1981 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Teacher's guide pamphlet titled "Crow Social Studies", 1986 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Photocopied research labeled "Absaroka - 1968" (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Crow-related research and correspondence, undated (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Crow research notes, undated (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Crow stories, research notes, undated (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Crow culture, research notes, undated (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Crow soul concepts, research notes, undated (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Crow medicine pipe and sweat lodge, research notes, undated (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Crow interview notes and other research, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - They Call Me Agnes research (including interview notes), 1993-1995 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Notes from interview with Helen (Pease) Wolf for They Call Me Agnes, 1980 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - One card titled "Crow - Orphans and the Sacred - Old Woman's Grandchild", undated (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Notes on Crow marriage, one interview note, 1939-08-12, undated (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Notes on Crow "Sex-Typing," interview notes, 1939, 1941, undated (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Notes on Crow virtue, undated (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Notes on Crow courtship, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Notes on Crow menstruation, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Note on Crow "Incense - Purification", undated (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Notes on Crow pregnancy and childbirth, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Notes on Crow pregnancy and birth practices, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Note on Crow abortion, undated (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Notes on Crow childcare, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Notes on Crow ear piercing, interview note, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Notes on Crow child growth ideas, interview note, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Notes on Crow weaning, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/19)
  - Notes on Crow childhood training, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Notes on Crow childhood play, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Notes on Crow teaching practices, undated (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Notes on Crow names and naming practices, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Notes on Crow medical practices, interview note, 1939, undated (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Note on Crow "curing" or healing practices, undated (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Notes on Crow perspectives toward diseases, sexual and other, interview note, 1939, and other undated (Box-folder 7/26)
  - Notes on Crow warfare, interview notes, 1939, undated (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Notes on Crow treatment of enemies, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Notes on Crow captives, undated (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Notes on Crow and other tribes' war lodges and camp structures, interviews, 1941 and other undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Notes on Crow warrior image and character, undated (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Note on Crow viewpoint toward reputation and special skills, undated (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Notes on Crow war party leadership, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Notes on reception of returning Crow war party, undated (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Notes on Crow coup, undated (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Notes on Crow "names - honor," interview, 1939, and other undated (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Notes on Crow "healing - military", undated (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Notes on Crow men's fraternities, undated (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Notes on Crow adults, undated (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Note on Crow youth, undated (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Notes on Crow religion, undated (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Notes on Crow creation myth, undated (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Notes on Crow deities or spirits, undated (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Notes on Crow "Little people or dwarfs", 1969-08-02 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Notes on Crow medicines, interview, 1939, undated (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Note on rock medicine, undated (Box-folder 8/20)
  - Notes on Crow fasting, undated (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Notes on Crow dreams and spirit encounters, interview, 1939-08-12, undated (Box-folder 8/22)
  - Interview with F. Lefthand on "No-Fire Beings", 1988-10-17 (Box-folder 8/23)
  - Notes on Crow medicine men, interviews, 1939, undated (Box-folder 8/24)
  - Notes on Crow church, interviews, 1939, 1940, undated (Box-folder 8/25)
  - Notes on Crow sacred tobacco, undated (Box-folder 8/26)
  - Notes on ritual diffusion of tobacco, undated (Box-folder 8/27)
  - Notes on Crow "tobacco, adoption - worship", undated (Box-folder 8/28)
  - Notes on Crow Sun Dance, undated (Box-folder 8/29)
  - Notes from early manuscripts of Yellowtail, Crow Medicine Man and Sun Dance Chief: an autobiography, respectively, final version published and notes approx. 1984, 1991; edited by Michael Oren Fitzgerald (Box-folder 8/30)
  - Telephone interview with Tom Yellowtail covering adoption, tobacco, Shoshoni Dance, and money tree, 1990-06-17 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Thank you note from Michael Fitzgerald, undated (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Magazine article about Thomas Yellowtail, 1993 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Thomas Yellowtail funeral program and obituary, 1993-11-20, 1993-12-06 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Notes labeled "informant accounts", 1984 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Notes on Crow "paint", undated (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Notes on Crow "respect," interview, 1980 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Notes on Crow "give-away," interview, 1941, 1980 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Interview with A.N. Thomas, 1941-10-21 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Notes on Crow use of and attitudes toward peyote, interview, 1941-05-27, and other undated (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Notes on Crow smoke - prayer, interviews, 1939 and 1980, and other undated (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Notes on Crow conflict and fighting, interview, 1939, and other undated (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Notes on Crow insult, undated (Box-folder 9/13)
  - Notes on Crow attitudes toward theft, interview, 1939, and other undated (Box-folder 9/14)
  - Note on Crow perspective of good and bad luck, undated (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Interview note regarding existence of Crow writing, undated (Box-folder 9/16)
  - Note from interview with Ball on Batsirupe, 1939-08-11 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - Notes on Crow council district, interviews, 1939 (Box-folder 9/18)